[SPEAKER_00]: yeah glory of their time remember that yeah and uh you were telling your own story you said you grew up in cleveland we're both from cleveland oh did you lakewood i see
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I lived in Lakewood, and she grew up in Cleveland Heights.
[SPEAKER_01]: And his dad was city engineer for the city of Cleveland, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just like your father was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sometime later.
[SPEAKER_03]: I used to build them all when I was playing ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Remember Patty Livingston?
[SPEAKER_03]: I talked to him a couple of years ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: He died in 1977.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was about 96 though.
[SPEAKER_03]: He lived on West 38th Street at that time.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Paddy was my first catcher I had.
[SPEAKER_00]: At Indianapolis?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, around Pershing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: Tellings Ice Cream and that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says in 1908, when you were with Indianapolis, you had a real good year there, he caught all your games.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is he a pretty good catcher?
[SPEAKER_03]: This is a great picture.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's a picture of my dad.
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember him so bad right now.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a really good guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you remember a chap named Durham, who was Indianapolis?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, Fulton Durham.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Livingston said he pitched five double-hitters that season.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is he that good?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he didn't have anything.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had a fastball, a hitter, an 8-year-old in there, and there was holes on the third base, and scores.
[SPEAKER_03]: He would stop for that.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was all right.
[SPEAKER_00]: You got sold for the biggest price ever to the Giants.
[SPEAKER_00]: The biggest sale price ever when Indianapolis sold you to the Giants, $11,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: Livingston said he wanted to go too, but he didn't go.
[SPEAKER_03]: where Paddy went to some time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went to Connie Mack.
[SPEAKER_00]: He played with Connie Mack for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was very catchy, Paddy, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: His fingers were all bent and broken.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was lost.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I tell ya, what's to be?
[SPEAKER_00]: August 2nd.
[SPEAKER_03]: August 2nd.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll be 98 pretty soon.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh my.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: You didn't think that?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I think you're in pretty good shape for 98.
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: I think you're in pretty good shape.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I was in good, real good shape until this accident.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that's...
[SPEAKER_03]: So I tell my supervisor, go on, go on, sit around the house, go on, lay down, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly
[SPEAKER_00]: You went on the stage for a while, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you play in regular plays or did you have a vaudeville act?
[SPEAKER_00]: What did you do?
[SPEAKER_03]: Mike Donovan did that too, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: There's a few things I remember.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can't remember.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever pitch against Ty Cobb?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never pitched against any old-time American league offers and especially exhibition.
[SPEAKER_00]: How about Hannes Wagner?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, he was a master lay-man.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was way fast.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I had no trouble with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pitch him outside?
[SPEAKER_03]: I was not bad with him, no, but I just controlled the class of the person.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's all.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rogers Hornsby, he probably pitched against him, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: When he came up later, it was very close.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was what they called a duck soup.
[SPEAKER_03]: I pitched against him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: I had control.
[SPEAKER_03]: I pitched to his weakness, see?
[SPEAKER_03]: Right over the plate.
[SPEAKER_03]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: And he fouled me.
[SPEAKER_03]: I pitched a bad ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were there any hitters that did give you a lot of trouble?
[SPEAKER_00]: Any hitters that gave you a lot of trouble?
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a history professor, is what he is.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's chairman of the history department at Marietta.
[SPEAKER_01]: And this is his hobby.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is what he really loves, is the history of baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: He teaches a course in it there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's a lot of fun, teaching baseball history.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I've interviewed a lot of other ball players, that's why I... You broke your leg in 1919.
[SPEAKER_00]: Remember that?
[SPEAKER_00]: How'd that happen?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was it in a game?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: He came back from there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you have anything?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I haven't.
[SPEAKER_00]: Are there any big thrills in your baseball career that stand out?
[SPEAKER_00]: I have a few, but...
[SPEAKER_00]: The no-hitter may be the best one, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, it is.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I don't give any more of it.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's kind of like you, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_03]: You get paid for it, and your life's crumpled up, and don't get it to die.
[SPEAKER_03]: All of you fellas, because you get free advertising and everything, want everything for nothing.
[SPEAKER_03]: And not do anything at all.
[SPEAKER_03]: This is for free advertising.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I don't do it that way.
[SPEAKER_02]: So,
[SPEAKER_03]: And whenever I got here, I made it so that my wife and I could be neighbors.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you've got a beautiful place here.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's gorgeous.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did your wife pick out the color scheme?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, she did a magnificent job.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never do everything at home.
[SPEAKER_03]: She and I were married 30 years.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh?
[SPEAKER_03]: 27 years, yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I let her be the boss of the house.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, that's nice.
[SPEAKER_03]: It is.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then you have two sons?
[SPEAKER_03]: I do.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, only four.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, step-sons.
[SPEAKER_03]: But real sons, I don't know if I got the real children of my own.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it's nice your stepson can come and go up to Cooperstown with you.
[SPEAKER_01]: It is.
[SPEAKER_03]: So, I'll be up the next Saturday.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm going to see my son.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I think it's great that you can get up there, because there's always such a good turnout up there, isn't there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, when you're alive.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Stanley Kovalevsky get up there very often?
[SPEAKER_03]: He's so alive.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a real nice day with him once, out in South Bend.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mrs. Kovalevsky said if he hadn't gotten into the hall of fame while he was still living, she didn't think she would have ever accepted it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I think you're getting ready to eat it looks like over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: They just set the table over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Looks like they're going to eat.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: for them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
Well, it certainly is lovely.
Boy, she sounded very nice on the phone.
She sounded very nice on the phone.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can imagine.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you still follow the game very much?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, a lot of the older ballplayers feel that way.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've got lots of company.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, we want to thank you very much for letting us see you and chat with you a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hope you have a real nice visit up to Cooperstown.
Yeah, that's great.
[SPEAKER_03]: Watch out for us.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Watch out here, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, OK.
[SPEAKER_03]: Had a great career.
[SPEAKER_03]: Must have had all kinds of thrills.
[SPEAKER_03]: Thank you so much.
I really appreciate it.
I wish I could have seen you sing.
[SPEAKER_03]: I came a little too late for that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Thanks again.
[SPEAKER_03]: Enjoy it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Have a nice visit.
Wasn't that a great interview?
Okay, here we are, several nights later.
This is Saturday night.
[SPEAKER_00]: August 4th, you're right.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we're in the 40 East Motel in Hagerstown, Maryland.
[SPEAKER_00]: We started this trip on Wednesday, August 1st.
[SPEAKER_00]: A little vacationing.
[SPEAKER_00]: tenting and baseballing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And on Wednesday, we traveled to Harper's Ferry and we camped at the KOA campground at Harper's Ferry.
[SPEAKER_00]: And on Thursday, we left the tent in place and drove to—first we drove to Baltimore for this interview, this great interview I was looking forward to so much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_05]: In Pikesville.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, at 11 Slade, a huge apartment complex in a place called Pikesville, just one of Baltimore's little suburbs.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then we were in here about, I don't know, 45 minutes or so.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then went on to Linthicum, Maryland, where I went to Bill Sanders and acquired some of his clippings.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then we drove back in the torrential downpour to our home away from home, our cozy little tent.
[SPEAKER_00]: which happily was not too wet, and we cleared the rest of the night.
[SPEAKER_00]: We stayed there on Thursday night.
[SPEAKER_00]: Friday we drove to Elkton, a pretty hard drive through Baltimore and around it and so on.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was pouring rain again, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it didn't rain.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was all the detours and all the traffic tie-ups.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of detours and tie-ups.
[SPEAKER_01]: And interstate.
[SPEAKER_00]: And accidents and things.
[SPEAKER_01]: All the way.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, interstate all the way.
[SPEAKER_00]: It took us a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: We thought we'd have plenty of time.
[SPEAKER_00]: We wanted to get there before 1, and we did, barely.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we negotiated the purchase of the Cleveland Indian scrapbooks from Tom Collier.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were hot, tired, exhausted, drained.
[SPEAKER_01]: Panicky.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was raining, or starting to.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess it wasn't starting to, but there was a forecast for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: We thought of tenting last night on the old campground, but we didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: We found a cozy little motel in Elkton called Clay's Motel.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is where we holed up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Got there about 2.30, I guess, and spent the rest of the day sorting things out.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had to repack the back of the car completely because of the weight of these
[SPEAKER_00]: There were some pretty heavy ones.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then we got up this morning, repacked this morning actually.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was torrential downpour after we got in the motel.
[SPEAKER_00]: It rained all afternoon and evening.
[SPEAKER_00]: We couldn't repack last evening because of the rain.
[SPEAKER_00]: So this morning we got up bright and early and repacked and we're off to King of Prussia in Philadelphia for the baseball convention.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we got there about 9.30 or so, and were there a couple of hours, had a breakfast, and left there at noon, heading back home.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we decided to stop down at Hagerstown tonight and interview Clyde Barnhart, which we just got through doing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Another tremendous interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: We called from Carlisle to make sure they were here before we came down, and maybe that was a mistake.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were very nice, but it wasn't that much.
[SPEAKER_00]: So now we'll talk about the Marquardt interview, such as it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: We could comment more on the interview than the interview could ever tell us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Take over.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm going to get a beer.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's in the, I put it in with the ice in the cooler.
[SPEAKER_01]: But we went in.
[SPEAKER_01]: The nurse was absolutely delightful.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she offered us a Coke, and she did everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then she went to bring him out in his wheelchair.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he came in.
[SPEAKER_01]: My boy's OK, you know that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He came out in his wheelchair, and oh, he was so gracious and nice and so pleased to see us.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Gene started asking him questions.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he started answering them.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then Gene asked him something about, what was your most thrilling moment?
[SPEAKER_01]: And he sat there for a minute.
[SPEAKER_01]: and said, who do you write for?
[SPEAKER_01]: And that was the end of his graciousness and everything else, as you could tell by listening to the tape.
[SPEAKER_01]: But to get back to his apartment, it's not an apartment the way you usually think of an apartment.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's one of these big, luxury, plush apartments.
[SPEAKER_01]: Apparently on this slate drive, there's a series of these.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sort of like the Gold Coast in Cleveland and that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there were three bedrooms in it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, of course, security guards, doorman, and reception at the desk that you had to go through to get to them.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the hallway, or the room, was like going into a motel foyer.
[SPEAKER_01]: with empire-style things and the craziest walls I ever saw.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of them were deep purple and light beige and then dark brown.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it sounds worse than it really looks.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's quite fancy.
[SPEAKER_01]: It must have been a modern decorator that did it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he went down a long corridor to get to their apartment, because we got to stay there on the first floor.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, uh, went in, and he went into their living room.
[SPEAKER_01]: And their living room, dining room area was one of these L-shaped things with windows all along one side looking out into the garden to this apartment complex.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there was a door that went out onto a little patio where I guess they could run his wheelchair.
[SPEAKER_01]: And those, I'll show you what kind of apartment it was, all those things, all those windows were wired
[SPEAKER_01]: for burglars.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so was the door.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the living room and dining room were done in blue and white.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it's the first time I think I have ever seen the walls were papered, or whatever you would call it, with like a blue patterned taffeta that was absolutely lush.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they had sterling silver all over the place.
[SPEAKER_01]: and a beautiful dining room set in their dining room area.
[SPEAKER_01]: And their stuffed furniture was all blue and white.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she had a modern card table.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, not a card table, but shaped like a card table.
[SPEAKER_01]: With big fancy legs on it, and then four plush chairs that moved around for her bridge club, because she plays a lot of bridge.
[SPEAKER_01]: But there was an awful lot of silver and stuff in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we didn't see any baseball stuff in there at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Gene had found out later that when they sold their house, they auctioned off all his baseball stuff.
[SPEAKER_01]: And a man bought it and sold it to this other chap, Sanders, for $50.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you know how much it went for.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Gene will tell you what it's like.
[SPEAKER_01]: The baseball stuff, some of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: What?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I've covered the apartment.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've covered the nurse.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you just, if she had been there, it might have been different.
[SPEAKER_01]: But she wasn't, so.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was Mrs. Marquardt?
[SPEAKER_01]: Mrs. Marquardt.
[SPEAKER_01]: But she plays a lot of golf and does a lot of swimming and plays a lot of bridge in that, so.
[SPEAKER_00]: They've been married 24 years, so that would take it back to 1955.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the present Mrs. Marquardt must be.
[SPEAKER_00]: His third wife, the sons he spoke of or she spoke of, may have been hers, he called him his stepson because he didn't have any of his own.
[SPEAKER_01]: That he knows of.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a dad.
[SPEAKER_00]: The collection of Mark Guardana that was auctioned included gloves, caps,
[SPEAKER_00]: plaques, trophies, guides, and probably much more.
[SPEAKER_00]: Those are the only things which were mentioned in kind of a rough way to catalog everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: One plaque he mentioned in particular was in honor of Marquardt's 19 straight victories in 1912, which is still a record.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was a pretty big plaque.
[SPEAKER_00]: It had each of those 19 victories noted on this plaque.
[SPEAKER_00]: One could well imagine what that item alone would bring today in an auction.
[SPEAKER_00]: All of this was done many years ago, the auctioning of the Marquardt Anna, which might explain why it went as cheap as it did then.
[SPEAKER_00]: It certainly wouldn't now.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm sure that apartment would cost every bit of $700 a month.
[SPEAKER_01]: They said $400 the other day.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've been thinking about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because it's just too large.
[SPEAKER_01]: And all those security features would be added.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because everybody came out with dripping.
[SPEAKER_01]: All those cars in the parking lot were Continentals and Cadillacs and things like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because everybody in the parking lot had their own number.
[SPEAKER_01]: own numbered parking space that they could drive into.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when they wanted their car, like that woman came in while we were there, and the man went and parked her car for her so she wouldn't have to get wet, the doorman or security guard uniform.
[SPEAKER_01]: And another one came down and he brought her car to her.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's not a cheap apartment.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rube Marquardt said he was 98 or going to be.
[SPEAKER_00]: He meant 90.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was born in 1889.
[SPEAKER_00]: This would make him 90.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a very handsome man, but he would be hardly recognizable today.
[SPEAKER_00]: The only recognizable part was his hair, which was still fairly full, but of course all gray now.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Marquardt's part, which is so well known in the pictures of him without his cap on,
[SPEAKER_00]: was still present, and a smiling face that's rather drained of any real understanding, it seemed like.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's just plain bitter, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: What he had experienced from writers, we can well imagine he does get into it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know how well the tape picked it up.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he asked me who I wrote for, there was a transition in the mood.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he suddenly, he didn't become totally hostile, but he just said he wouldn't give out any more information now.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd give a little bit, but not much more.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not that he'd given out that much anyhow.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he said all they want to do is to advertise themselves and make a name for themselves, and he and others like him would get nothing from it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was so taken aback by the question, I didn't really know how to answer it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: I kind of fumbled through there for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: It didn't take long to figure out what his animus was.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was deep.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there was no point in trying to fight it because he couldn't understand you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's just unfortunate that I came so late.
[SPEAKER_00]: By that, I mean 10 years late, because I know he was such a good interviewee and always willing to take part in programs or panel discussions with old players.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had so much to say.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think Lawrence Ritter is the one that finished him off.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you mention Ritter's book in the interview?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I don't know if that would have done it.
[SPEAKER_00]: There must have been some others, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I'm sure there have been others.
[SPEAKER_01]: I really got a lot of publicity out of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was easy to see right away it was going to be a useless interview, as far as really getting into some of the things I wanted to get into.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a good thing you got his autograph before he got this bee in his bonnet.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, the first thing we did, and we always do that, is get him to autograph the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: In this case, the first day cover from Cooperstown in 1939 when he opened the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_00]: He did that right away.
[SPEAKER_00]: And his writing was fairly legible.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had some trouble with the baseball, because he ran into Joey Sewell when he was only up to MAR.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I had to tell him to write the quart a little bit higher up.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it's a split-level autograph.
[SPEAKER_00]: It began to rain cats and dogs out in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: One buddy, who was it that you interviewed that had sent Ash, was that who it was?
[SPEAKER_05]: Ash that had sent the baseball hat?
[SPEAKER_05]: Who did he play for, Brooklyn?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, whoever it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had played for Brooklyn, and he had sent his own baseball cap to somebody to have them autograph it, and they never sent it back to him.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, he was mad at that.
[SPEAKER_04]: I'll bet.
[SPEAKER_04]: All he ever gets is this stuff.
[SPEAKER_04]: Most of them send self-addressed envelopes.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's a little harsh, you know.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, well, they should, because that mounts up in voltage if you had that.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: I mean, he always loved, you know, loved about him, but he always picked and let him out, right?
[SPEAKER_05]: Yeah, well, that makes sense.
[SPEAKER_05]: You know, I think that's good.
[SPEAKER_05]: Because, uh...
[SPEAKER_05]: He had a great grandson.
[SPEAKER_04]: He still collects the cards, you know, he doesn't have any other gifts, but he collects the baseball cards.
[SPEAKER_04]: He had a great grandson?
[SPEAKER_05]: Oh, yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_05]: Oh, really?
[SPEAKER_05]: Oh, boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got one card yesterday.
[SPEAKER_02]: I told them about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just one card.
[SPEAKER_04]: The first one I ever got.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's 10 cents.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just a card.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was just a regular government card.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some would send two or three cards.
[SPEAKER_02]: Gosh, some of them would send dozens.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I've got to get the camera.
[SPEAKER_02]: You do?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's in there with a mandolin.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, why don't you get that, and then maybe you can get a copy of it and send it back to them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Out of camera here, we can take a picture of pictures.
[SPEAKER_04]: Mary Pickford died.
[SPEAKER_04]: They was out in Paso Robles.
[SPEAKER_04]: And they was out there where they were.
[SPEAKER_04]: Wasn't that the day?
[SPEAKER_04]: And took their picture.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh?
[SPEAKER_04]: It was then.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that very nice paper was where she had died.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was getting embarrassing, because he wanted copies of the picture.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he hated to ask those men for them, because even a copy runs you into money.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we didn't think that was fair.
[SPEAKER_01]: So finally, he got a camera.
[SPEAKER_01]: He borrowed a camera from the college is what he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was a nervous wreck when he had it, because he borrowed it from one of the departments in the college.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it was something like $400.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, it was an expensive camera.
[SPEAKER_01]: When we take it on a trip, I get bothered.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he finally got this camera, and it's certainly not a $400 camera.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it does take pictures.
[SPEAKER_01]: And this is the one that he used to take the picture for the rights, that they wanted copies made.
[SPEAKER_04]: Can you see?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you need a light?
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: This is the thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he doesn't need a flash tube or anything.
[SPEAKER_04]: There's a little light back there in the corner, but I don't know if you can turn it on.
[SPEAKER_04]: This is what he brings me along for.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or can you get it yourself?
[SPEAKER_01]: I never smoke when I go on the interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm getting a hilly conscience about my smoking.
[SPEAKER_04]: I said I was going to quit when I was 80.
[SPEAKER_04]: I told my granddaughter last week, I think a couple of days ago, I'm going to quit when I'm 80.
[SPEAKER_04]: She said, ah, you told me that before.
[SPEAKER_05]: I said, well, I didn't say 80 how much.
[SPEAKER_05]: I keep thinking I'm going to quit.
[SPEAKER_05]: But I never quite get around to it.
[SPEAKER_04]: There's a picture in there of the light when you pass around.
[SPEAKER_04]: This was a very big picture.
[SPEAKER_04]: This was back in the 1990s.
[SPEAKER_05]: I didn't see a lot of pictures that you don't want to take.
[SPEAKER_04]: We had a great big one back in the den, but you wouldn't want to miss a great big picture.
[SPEAKER_03]: One more.
[SPEAKER_04]: You want a copy?
[SPEAKER_04]: I meant, you wouldn't want to take a picture of that, would you?
[SPEAKER_04]: I'll be right with you.
[SPEAKER_04]: You give a film of my husband?
[SPEAKER_05]: I don't even know if you can get it.
[SPEAKER_05]: It's a great big picture.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got my laundry piled up back there.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can wade through it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Listen, my house looked like a disaster area when I left it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And our daughter said, well, Mom, she said, I thought I'd come home this weekend.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, well, we're not going to be there, honey.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she said, oh, that's all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of the people where I work want to know where I live.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she said, I said, I live in a big, old-fashioned house, because we've got 12 rooms in it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it's a monstrosity room.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she said, so we'll just drop in for a few minutes.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, well, if you expect me to have this house clean when you get, you bring your friends in on Friday night, which would be tonight, or last night.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, you've got nothing coming.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, because I know I will not have it done.
[SPEAKER_01]: She said, well, that's all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Don't worry.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I, I, maybe she thought I really would, but I didn't.
[SPEAKER_04]: I have laundry in the utility room.
[SPEAKER_04]: I thought, now that I have my own trading woman, she comes on a Tuesday.
[SPEAKER_04]: And I thought, well, I'll call her before and see if I could get her to trade with another woman and let her come Monday, and then my house would be clean Tuesday when you folks come.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, well, the thing was that we left on Wednesday.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then after he got these grants, we were going to stay in Philadelphia at night.
[SPEAKER_01]: But after he got these scrapbooks, I got panicky about driving home across the mountains.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so we decided we would just come.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we debated, should we come down to Hagerstown or shouldn't we?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, well, you said next week, maybe we shouldn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I know, but I'm so close.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, you can't ask me to pass this up.
[SPEAKER_01]: So down we came.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I'll call him from Carlisle and ask him if I can come.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he didn't say where he was calling from, and I know nothing about 81.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, but we called from Pennsylvania Turnpike is where he called from.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because if it hadn't been convenient, then we would have kept on going.
[SPEAKER_01]: We would have.
[SPEAKER_01]: But we've been there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we went once last year.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had just gotten his car.
[SPEAKER_01]: And our transmission went out to Palm Springs.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we were stuck there for five days.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so this kind of, then when he wanted to interview ball players that were up in, well, I won't tell you where some of them were.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he would need a four-wheel drive to get up to them, because they'd be up on the top of mountains, and there would be nothing for miles.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he'd say, should we?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'd say, no, I don't think we should.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so, we had to go to the ones that were nice and accessible, like Glen Rice and some of those others that were here in the Napa Valley and that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Doing any good?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I hope so.
[SPEAKER_05]: Have you got them on lightning or set right or whatever it is?
[SPEAKER_03]: It doesn't take newspaper pictures too well, but it does.
[SPEAKER_03]: It takes them.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had the glossy hair that you could get a good picture of.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, right over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: On the table.
[SPEAKER_01]: You could get the picture of him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I like it because you don't need glasses with it.
[SPEAKER_01]: We went up to
[SPEAKER_01]: He was on his way to a history convention.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we stopped at Joe McCarthy's house.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we had the college camera that time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never.
[SPEAKER_03]: What are these two over there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you know who these two are?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's me and this is the other one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah, there are two of them.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's the main and the under.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's the 25th
[SPEAKER_04]: Here's one that she was talking about.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's, uh... You know that part?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I spent an evening with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hoi Hoi.
[SPEAKER_05]: Oh, Hoi Hoi.
[SPEAKER_05]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_05]: Oh!
[SPEAKER_05]: Yeah, I don't remember him.
[SPEAKER_05]: Now you know why he brings me.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, I'm fine.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's a nice trip.
[SPEAKER_00]: Very good.
Twenty-five, staring.
Oh, what is that?
Oh, one plus five, that is... Oh, did they?
[SPEAKER_04]: He was late a couple of years after he went out of service.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was in the hospital for a very long time.
[SPEAKER_04]: He didn't last very long.
[SPEAKER_05]: He didn't last very long.
He didn't last very long.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't last very long.
[SPEAKER_03]: He didn't last very long.
He didn't last very long.
[SPEAKER_03]: He didn't last very long
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, it's you and I.
[SPEAKER_04]: You and I. Oh, it's the boys.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, daddy.
[SPEAKER_04]: He'll be in there, he'll be 12 in November, he'll be in there.
[SPEAKER_05]: What's called a senior, you know, next year, he'll be 16 years.
[SPEAKER_05]: If he wants to be a ball player when he grows up.
[SPEAKER_05]: He does, the burden says he'll never make it.
[SPEAKER_05]: Oh, really?
[SPEAKER_05]: I've never seen him play.
[SPEAKER_05]: He went out a couple of times.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, great-grandpa probably knows.
[SPEAKER_05]: Sit out there on a little hard bench, not for me.
[SPEAKER_02]: You won't try what you're told him to do.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, I'll tell you about these little things.
[SPEAKER_04]: There's too many parents go.
[SPEAKER_04]: They'd stay at home and let the kids, take the kids.
[SPEAKER_04]: But now it's just taking them, you know, and all that.
[SPEAKER_04]: And it's a lot of bothering, a lot of trouble.
[SPEAKER_04]: Now it's high as jazz is.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, our little, our boyfriend's got a little leaf ball, but we didn't go and watch him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then he played Little League football.
[SPEAKER_04]: We'd go and watch that.
[SPEAKER_04]: He said he wasn't going to play this year.
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't know if he will now.
[SPEAKER_05]: I hope he doesn't.
[SPEAKER_05]: I don't like football.
[SPEAKER_05]: Yeah, and you know, our son is not a violent person.
[SPEAKER_05]: And he just loves football.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the wetter it was, and the muddier the field, and the dirtier he got, the happier he was.
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't remember when he did that picture.
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't remember seeing it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he sent that to somebody else.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was it?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: What are you going to do with all those clippings that aren't in the book?
[SPEAKER_00]: Are you going to put them in the book?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: My daughter-in-law on the deck can take those clippings out and make a new book, but if you'd ever try to take those old clippings out of there, they don't hold.
[SPEAKER_05]: What did she mind taking them out for?
[SPEAKER_05]: Put them in a new book.
[SPEAKER_05]: But this is a good book.
[SPEAKER_05]: With the wrong binding, and the paper's good, and well-knotted.
[SPEAKER_04]: I was an only child myself.
[SPEAKER_01]: And yet, you know, we've talked to some players and their families couldn't care less.
[SPEAKER_01]: They don't want to think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you know all of Rube Marquardt's things were auctioned off?
[SPEAKER_01]: Everything he had, he got rid of when they sold their house.
[SPEAKER_05]: Doesn't he have any children?
[SPEAKER_05]: No.
[SPEAKER_05]: He had two step-sons.
[SPEAKER_05]: Step-son.
[SPEAKER_05]: Second wife.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because, uh...
[SPEAKER_01]: I was gonna turn this tape recorder off, so I'm not the one that's on it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm doing all the...
[SPEAKER_02]: I got it out of his collection.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then he went to fetch it out and put it right where it was.
[SPEAKER_03]: What, in the Frederick uniform?
[SPEAKER_05]: No, that's where he got it from.
[SPEAKER_05]: I'll put it up here so you can see it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you win the batting championship with Frederick?
[SPEAKER_00]: You seem to be fighting for the title there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he beat me out by a couple points, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: He got two hits and he was a manager, see, and he took himself out of the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he wouldn't get any outs.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got two hits.
[SPEAKER_02]: What kind of ballparks do they have in the Blue Ridge Lake?
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you see many people or have good locker rooms?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, they were just cheap things.
[SPEAKER_02]: Frederick, they had theirs over there at the fairground.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hagerstown, I think they had theirs out there at their locker room out at the fairground.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't remember where Martin's Park was, or Gettysburg.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ever heard of any of the plank boys?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, first I spoke to them.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're from Gettysburg, aren't they?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did you travel?
[SPEAKER_00]: By bus or train?
[SPEAKER_00]: By bus.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you have any overnight stops?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: How about crowds?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you have very big crowds at the movies?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, not much.
[SPEAKER_04]: There, get that one back there where you started.
[SPEAKER_04]: BBCA or Buckeye Valley Athletic Club.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's the first one to go down.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, it's in there.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's on the first page, yeah.
[SPEAKER_05]: That was down below our house.
[SPEAKER_05]: Could you do each one separately?
[SPEAKER_05]: This is 1920.
Again now?
Bye.
[SPEAKER_00]: Billy Southworth was with the team then, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: In 1920?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you played with a lot of
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of greats and near-greats, haven't you?
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a wonderful career.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wish I could have played baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just had to envy those who could.
[SPEAKER_04]: I mean, it's all right for the ball players, and it's all right for somebody who doesn't have children to, you know, go and stay on.
[SPEAKER_01]: I forget that so many of the people that came to his interviews had a men's hair.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were the pirates a pretty well-behaved club to your day?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't go out in the town every night or get into trouble?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: No?
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, they were doing prohibition, so it couldn't be too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they had their beer joints where I could go and get a beer after the ball game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that permitted?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ironville.
[SPEAKER_02]: Remember him?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was our shortstop for a few years.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was a stomach catcher.
[SPEAKER_04]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_04]: Shortstop.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Didn't he always catch them down there in his stomach?
[SPEAKER_05]: He was good.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I enjoyed this very much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's pretty great.
[SPEAKER_00]: I appreciate you letting me come in here and talking with you and hearing you talk about your career.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'll be walking down here.
[SPEAKER_01]: He won't be able to wait now until I get those pictures developed.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I'll get them developed.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, they're pretty good originals.
[SPEAKER_04]: Some of those pictures, you know, have taken off.
[SPEAKER_04]: Here we are again.
[SPEAKER_04]: Back in our cozy little motel.
[SPEAKER_00]: Saturday night, the same night, in fact, we made the comments on the other side of this tape about Rube Marquardt.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get them all on the one tape?
[SPEAKER_00]: All what?
[SPEAKER_00]: I got Marquardt and his comments on the other side of this tape.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, the tape that flip-flopped.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I didn't use this tape at all, the other side, because of the clicking noise.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, all I can say is, after listening to this tape,
[SPEAKER_01]: I spoke a lot of drivel trying to keep them happy.
[SPEAKER_00]: You were great.
[SPEAKER_01]: I sound off and on.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you made them feel.
[SPEAKER_00]: Exaggerate.
[SPEAKER_00]: You made them feel relaxed.
[SPEAKER_00]: You smoothed out the interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: You brought her into it nicely.
[SPEAKER_01]: Only to keep them happy.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I think, you know when I think about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Speak up.
[SPEAKER_01]: With her five, well, I'll be honest with you.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm worried about you.
[SPEAKER_01]: She said that they stayed in Hagerstown, and when he was playing in Pittsburgh, she would drive over.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then after they left on the road, she would drive back.
[SPEAKER_01]: Must have been something in those days for a woman to drive like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they didn't have any interstates then either.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, and that would be a drive from Hagerstown to Pittsburgh to mow.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it would be an all-day adventure.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm sure it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: For two weeks.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were driving home this afternoon, Saturday, August 4th, 1979, along the Pennsylvania Turnpike from the King of Prussia Inn, where we had the baseball convention this morning.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we didn't know whether to go down to Barnards or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd called them earlier, a couple of days ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: exciting a prospect from Mrs. Barnhart's response.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we called them, and if we could see them tonight, and they said, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we went on down to Eggerstown then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we got a motel room.
[SPEAKER_00]: We got two motel rooms in one night, incidentally.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that's another story.
[SPEAKER_00]: We don't have as much space on this table as any other one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we didn't want to stay at the Ramada Inn or the Howley Inn or the Quality Inns.
[SPEAKER_00]: We didn't feel rich enough at Great Western.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we were looking for some low-budget motels for this night, since we really would like to have camped.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a beautiful day.
[SPEAKER_00]: We didn't have enough time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mother wanted to camp, but I had to talk her out of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we were looking for a budget motel, and we found the Waterview Motel.
[SPEAKER_00]: out here on the eastern edges of Hagerstown.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we went there, and there was nobody in, and the paint was falling off, and it looked like it was an abandoned barracks of some sort.
[SPEAKER_01]: You rang the bell?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, did the bell ring?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not going to believe you.
[SPEAKER_00]: So then we were going to leave and go someplace else, and we pulled out onto the main road 40, US 40 East, and there right across was the most inviting-looking bit of hostelry called the Antietam Motel.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we went in there, and the people were very nice up in the front room.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we got back to our room number 10, and it was a disgrace.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were the only people in the motel at the one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: That made us suspicious.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went in there, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: The place was rather drab and barren.
[SPEAKER_00]: One light, one straight back chair.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't go off in the bathroom.
[SPEAKER_00]: And use soap in the bathroom.
[SPEAKER_00]: I would pull the bedsheets back so I could prop the pillow up and watch the ball game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the bed hadn't been made up.
[SPEAKER_03]: The bedsheets were dirty.
[SPEAKER_00]: Imagine our shock.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, it takes quite a bit for us to go to the management and complain.
[SPEAKER_00]: But this time, we didn't complain.
[SPEAKER_00]: We just went in and wanted our money back and took it and left.
[SPEAKER_00]: They weren't going to have anything to do with that place.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we came out farther in East 40 and found here a lovely little motel at 40 East.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we went down to Richardson's for supper at about quarter of 6.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I interviewed at quarter of 7 out in Funkstown, 22